Ride together. Die together.
Bad Boys for Life is a thriller, action, crime film directed by Bilall Fallah.
Marcus and Mike are forced to confront new threats, career changes, and midlife crises as they join the newly created elite team AMMO
of the Miami police department to take down the ruthless Armando Armas, the vicious leader of a Miami drug cartel.
Mike, played by Will Smith.
Marcus, played by Martin Lawrence.
Kelly, played by Vanessa Hudgens.
Dorn, played by Alexander Ludwig.
Rafe, played by Charles Melton.
Rita, played by Paola Nuñez.
Bad Boys for Life is a 2020 American buddy cop action comedy film that is the sequel to
Bad Boys II (2003) and the third installment in the Bad Boys franchise.
Will Smith and Martin Lawrence reprise their starring roles in the
film, which is directed by Adil El Arbi and Bilall Fallah.
Theresa Randle and Joe Pantoliano also reprise previous roles and are joined by Vanessa Hudgens,
Alexander Ludwig, Paola Núñez, Charles Melton, Kate del Castillo, and Nicky Jam.
The film was produced by Smith, Jerry Bruckheimer, and Doug Belgrad, with a
screenplay written by Chris Bremner, Peter Craig, and Joe Carnahan.
In the film, Miami detectives Mike Lowrey and Marcus Burnett
investigate a string of murders tied to Lowrey's troubled past.
A third Bad Boys film was contemplated following the release of the second film in 2003, with Michael Bay stating
he would be interested in returning to direct, but budgetary constraints led to stalled efforts.
Over the years, a variety of writers and directors were attached as the
film went through multiple attempts to enter production.
The project was eventually finalized and green-lit in October 2018, and filming
began the following year, lasting from January to June 2019.
Principal photography took place in Atlanta, Miami, and Mexico City.
Bad Boys for Life was theatrically released in the United States on January 17,
2020, by Sony Pictures Releasing under the Columbia Pictures label.
The film was generally well received by critics and grossed $426.5 million
worldwide, becoming the third-highest-grossing January release of all time.
It was also the highest-grossing film of the year domestically in the United States, the
fourth-highest-grossing film of 2020 and the highest-grossing film in the franchise.
A sequel, Bad Boys: Ride or Die, was released on June 7, 2024.
The film explores themes of mexico, miami, florida,
detective, women's prison, sequel.
The tone is intense.